what you're looking at is a spider robot
drone that's operated by a tiny
disembodied human brain you know the
brain organoids that can be grown from
stem cells we'll talk about this
experiment and some of the very real
ethics what they wanted to do was
actually give the brain organoids
something to interact with giving the
little brain a body to Pilot will allow
them to investigate human brain
development with actual stimuli one of
the big problems with trying to make
organoids is not having anything for
them to do the only slice of development
that we really get is what a brain might
develop into with nothing going on no
input until this last year the only way
to keep them alive long term was to put
them in a mouse's or rat's brain which I
know is a little spooky this actually
showed that they could repair a damaged
part of a brain and it turns out our
neurons don't mind making connections
with something that isn't human however
some scientists were able to create
vasculature and a bloodb brain barrier
by combining them with a vascular
organoid so we could potentially keep
them alive for a lot longer now a lot of
people have asked me where does ethic
come into this equation and where do
they actually come from well there are
two methods of making them you can use
either a skin spell from donated tissue
or fetal brain tissue somewhat
unfortunately the question of how we
should govern the use of brain organoids
came a little bit after we already
started doing it some researchers have
proposed that people have more informed
consent if their tissue that they've
donated is going to end up being a
potentially conscious robot maybe they
should know and yes researchers are
considering the possibility of creating
Consciousness and whether or not brain
organoids should be treated as a
research subject or an object these
ideas are not that outlandish